Guide to the Gil J Wolman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1937-1995; Series IX; .42; (1 box)
  Organized alphabetically by document type.
  Series IX. contains photographs, obituaries, newsletters, and other papers relating to Wolman's personal life, including to his youth before joining the Lettrist movement and to his political activism.
  - Account book for clothing manufacture, 1937-1940 (Box 55, Folder 709)
  - Adress book, undated (Box 55, Folder 710)
  - Address file, undated (Box 55, Folder 711)
    - Fragile original on thermal paper (Box 67, Folder 835)
  - Addresses, undated (Box 55, Folder 712)
    Notes and empty envelopes kept by Wolman in a separate file as reference for addresses.
  - Cadavres exquis and chess game notations, undated (Box 55, Folder 713)
  - Continuing education cards at the Université de Paris, 1980-1981 (Box 55, Folder 714)
  - Death act and obituaries for Wolman, 1995- (Box 55, Folder 715)
    - Fragile newspaper clippings (Box 67, Folder 836)
  - Death notices and obituary for Jean Louis Brau and Louis Brau, 1985-1987 (Box 55, Folder 716)
  - Dedication page from Paul Éluard, Choix de poèmes (Paris: Gallimard, 1941), undated (Box 55, Folder 717)
    With autograph dedication "À Joseph Wolman - en souvenirs, Paul Élouard". Accompanied by other pages from the volume.
  - Dedication page from Jules Romains, autograph note to unknown recipient, undated (Box 55, Folder 718)
  - Front page from Ce soir newspaper, 1945-06-14 (Box 58 (Oversize), Folder 755)
  - Juvenalia file "Personnel Gil", 1943-1956 (Box 55, Folder 719-720)
    Includes a membership card with the Union de la jeunesse juive (1944), cards for the Union française des auberges de la jeunesse (1947-1949), foreign currencies, bank receipts, transportation receipts, and undated holograph text on meeting Charlotte Wolman.
  - Newsletter of the Comités des quartiers pour la paix au Vietnam, [1968] (Box 55, Folder 721)
  - Newsletter of the Conseil local du mouvement de la paix (Aubervilliers), [1968] (Box 55, Folder 722)
  - Note on Combat newspaper letterhead, circa 1945 (Box 55, Folder 723a)
  - Passport and other identification cards, circa 1980 - 1989 (Box 55, Folder 723b)
  - "Petits papiers" short notes for game, undated (Box 55, Folder 724)
    Possibly a cadavre exquis cut into its individual components.
  - Photographs of Wolman, 1954-1993 (Box 55, Folder 725-726)
    Contains seventeen photographic prints of Wolman working in his studio, posing in front of his artwork, and posing with friends (Piero and Helena Simondo, Anne Zamire, Dominique Meens, Jean-Michel and Marie-Madeleine Mension).
  - Photographs of others, undated (Box 55, Folder 727)
    Contains one portrait of "Bernard Bengager dit Bubu", and one photocopy of a 1954 photograph of Pinot Gallizio.
  - Political ephemera, circa 1955-1970 (Box 55, Folder 728)
  - Postcards "Photosillons 33 tours", blank, undated (Box 55, Folder 729)
  - Poster "Elections" with text by Karl Marx, undated (Box 61 (Oversize), Folder 781)
  - Sepulchre location for [François] Dufrêne, undated (Box 55, Folder 730)
  - Share certificate ("action artistique") for Stéphane Chaumet, 1992-12-11- (Box 55, Folder 731)
  - Statutes and newsletter for the Société de la propriété artistique des dessins et modèles (SPADEM), 1981-06- (Box 55, Folder 732)
  - Travel ephemera, circa 1950-1982 (Box 55, Folder 733)
  - Wedding invitation for Wolman and Violette Brassard, 1953-12-19- (Box 55, Folder 734)